LINDSAY NEAL

www.lindsaykneal.com

neal1191@gmail.com

EDUCATION

University of Kansas

December 2013

Bachelor of Science in Journalism, strategic communication emphasis.

Minor in Psychology, with additional courses in Business

Johnson County Community College

December 2015

Associate of Applied Science in Web Development and Digital Media. Concentration in Desktop Publishing

OVERVIEW OF SKILLS

Skilled at creating strategic planning and advertising executions; conducting and documenting research; crafting blog and social media posts; writing and producing television and radio commercials; writing print ads and news releases.

Experienced at designing and developing websites; creating digital content, both written content and visual graphics.

Strong understanding of user experience design, search engine optimization and analytics.

Proficient with Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign. Experience with content management systems (Wordpress, Drupal) and front-end frameworks (Bootstrap).

Core languages: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Ajax.

EXPERIENCE

Web Designer - SoftScience Group, Inc., 6/2015 - present

Built and developed core company websites and other client websites. Tasks include front-end coding, UI/UX design (wireframes/mock-ups), content development (research, writing, graphics).

Cake Artist/Owner - Sweet Nothings Cakes, 8/2009 - present

Founded a specialty cake design and production, part-time business as a creative outlet.

Barista - Caribou Coffee, 12/2013- 6/2015

Worked 20 - 30 hours each week to pay for college expenses.

Bakery Assistant - *Hy-Vee*, *Inc.*, 8/2010 - 12/2013

Worked 20 - 30 hours each week to pay for college expenses.

ACTIVITIES

Lead To Read

Serve KC

JoCo DEMS

Reader - Spend one day a week reading with a 1st grader to improve basic reading skills.

Member - Volunteered for non-profits such as the Ronald McDonald House, Harvesters, and Giving The Basics.

Communications Committee - Created a blog and promotional materials (handouts and signs).